amc.edu 2006-06-30

# Web Privacy Statement

|  | 

|   
  
---  
  
|  | 

| 

**_Albany Medical Center_** ** __**

| 

|   
---|---|---|---|---  
|  | 

Consumer Website Privacy Statement

**Introduction  
** Your Privacy is important to us at Albany Medical Center (AMC). The only information AMC obtains about individual visitors to this website is information supplied voluntarily by the visitor. This statement outlines the policies and practices of AMC regarding the collection and use of your personal information from your visit to our website. AMC has created this privacy statement to demonstrate our commitment to maintain the privacy of visitors to our website. 

**_WARNING_ :** This website is not a resource for providing medical advice. This site, its information and its resources are not intended to be a substitute for professional medical advice. Nothing in this site is intended to be used for medical diagnosis or treatment.  If you submit an inquiry that contains your or someone else's health care information, care, condition or needs, our staff will not respond by providing medical advice to you. AMC will however attempt to direct you to the appropriate health care professional to assist you. 

**Information Collected  
** The personal information we collect depends on how you choose to make use of our website. We will not collect any identifying or personal information about you unless you deliberately submit such information in the course of paying a bill or making a billing inquiry. 

Any communication concerning your personal health information is protected by federal law and AMC's own privacy practices both of which can be found by following the link to our Notice of Privacy Practices or by finding this link on AMC's homepage.

  1. **General website usage information  
** To monitor site usage and improve the quality of our website, we gather general information about the use of our site. The information collected does not identify you personally, but provides us with ``usage data" such as the number of website visitors or the pages visited most often.  We do not track individual users visit to our website.  The usage data collected help us analyze and improve the quality and efficiency of our website. 

The usage data is able to be collected through the use of cookies. Cookies are small data files that are sent by a website and stored on your computer.  Cookies are used by most websites.  Cookies can contain information about your use of our website, but they are not used to identify or track you personally.  Cookies allow us to make it easier for you to log-in again when you return to this site.  If you use a password protected element of this website, we may use cookies to help us recognize you and maintain your preferences. 

Cookies you receive from AMC's website do not contain any personally identifiable information. We do not use cookies for advertising or other commercial purposes. AMC's website only uses cookies when they offer significant convenience or added benefit to you, or when the software we use requires their use. If you do not wish to accept cookies from our website or any others, use your Internet Options or Preference feature on your browser to turn off your automatic acceptance of cookies. You should be aware that significant portions of our website will not function properly if you do not accept cookies.

  2. **Personal Information Collected to Process Transactions  
** In using some of AMC's services in this website, it may be necessary to request of you personal information necessary to process the transaction. This may include your name, address, telephone and fax numbers, e-mail address and credit card number or other payment information. The personal information you provide is encrypted and sent to us using a secure means of transmittal. However, please understand that no one can give an absolute assurance that information intended to be maintained as private, whether transmitted via the internet or otherwise, cannot be accessed inappropriately or unlawfully by third parties.  We have taken and will continue to take reasonable steps to ensure the secure and safe transmission of your personal information. 

Personal information submitted by you will only be viewed by our staff to respond to your inquiry or process your information. On occasion, employees or contractors may view personal information in the course of providing technical assistance to maintain and improve our website. or in the course of receiving training relating to our website. We will not disclose your personal information to third parties unless authorized by you or required to do so by law.

  3. **Payment Method Information  
** Payment information, such as information contained on your credit card, is collected only to process a transaction and obtained and stored in an encrypted format. While being used to process the transaction, your payment information is stored in an encrypted format and reasonable measures are taken to ensure your payment information is not vulnerable to theft or interception.  We will not store or distribute your payment information in a manner that is not necessary for processing your transaction.  You are always welcome to use traditional means such as the telephone or mail in transmitting your personal information to us.
  4. **Links to Other Websites  
** AMC's website may contain links to other websites. We provide these links for the convenience of visitors to the AMC site. AMC makes no representations regarding the information contained in the sites linked to this website or the privacy or security practices of those other sites. AMC is not responsible for the content nor the privacy practices of the other linked websites. Please check with the other sites to determine their privacy polices and the collection and use of information.
  5. **Changes to this Statement  
** The terms, policy and practices contained within this Privacy Statement will be updated and/or modified periodically to reflect new features or services.  It is your responsibility to review our Privacy Statement on a regular basis to familiarize yourself with relevant changes to the policy that may affect you. The privacy statement was last up-dated on **2/12/04.** ****
  6. **Notice Concerning Minors  
** This website is not intended for use by minors.  If you are under eighteen years of age, you may not use the services within this website and you should not provide information to AMC without the supervision and consent of a parent or guardian.
  7. **Changes to Your Non-Health Related Information  
** You can request the individual, non-health related information that AMC has collected concerning you for the purpose of reviewing and/or editing your information. 
  8. **Changes to Your Health Related Information  
** If you wish to review and/or edit your personal health information, known as your protected health information (PHI) you must go to AMC's privacy practices webpage which can be accessed by the following link, Notice of Privacy Practices or by selecting this link at AMC's homepage, _www.amc.edu_.
  9. **Legal Disclaimer  
** Unfortunately, no data protection method or combination of methods can be guaranteed as 100 percent secure. AMC is not responsible for and will not be held liable for disclosures of your personal information due to errors in transmission or unauthorized acts of third parties. AMC cannot guarantee the privacy of your confidential information transmitted to its website should you chose not to use the appropriate secure on-line forms provided in the relevant pages of the website. By using this website you agree to the terms and conditions outlined in this policy statement, as well as those contained in our Notice of Privacy Practices governing both AMC's and your, rights and responsibilities with respect to your individually identifiable health information in compliance with the Federal Government's Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) of 1996, Public Law 104-191.

|  |   
|  |  |   
| 

|  | 

|   
  
|  |   
  
See your health care provider for specific medical advice. AMC takes no responsibility for content provided at external link sites.  
 **Copyright, 2002-2004, Albany Medical Center. All Rights Reserved** ****
